<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peterborough.tech-community.co.uk</title>
    <description>Free and open source blog for IT professionals in Peterborough. Populated by anybody thats has any kind of interest in IT.
We are always looking for contributors.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 16:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 16:15:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natural Agile - Let&#39;s take agile back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fellow Humans,&lt;br /&gt;
At this profound point in my agile journey I look around me and despair as I witness &lt;em&gt;organisation&lt;/em&gt; after &lt;em&gt;organisation&lt;/em&gt; drowning in a sea of confusion about what agile is and what it is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desperate to transform in order to survive in an ever changing, ever more competitive commercial world, organisations reach out to ‘&lt;em&gt;agile professionals&lt;/em&gt;’ for help, but all too often their trust is met by ‘&lt;em&gt;consultants&lt;/em&gt;’ peddling ‘&lt;em&gt;snake oil agile&lt;/em&gt;’ that do nothing more than act in their own self-interest and implement &lt;strong&gt;hollow&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt;flaccid&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;processes&lt;/strong&gt; that loosely resemble something taken from a book or watched on you-tube. They have &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; concept or interest in the true essence of agile. The disillusioned, victim organisations are dragged further under-water and ‘agile’ takes the blame. It is not good. &lt;strong&gt;It makes me sad :(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; lost … I sense an emerging undercurrent, a backlash from the originators of agile and the &lt;em&gt;frustrated&lt;/em&gt; many that try to hold true the vision of the original manifesto. It is my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;humble&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; intention to try to create a spark, in the hope that it will unite and mobilise this groundswell of frustration and turn it into &lt;strong&gt;positive action&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agile I believe in &lt;strong&gt;empowers&lt;/strong&gt; the individual, &lt;strong&gt;elevates&lt;/strong&gt; the team and promotes genuine &lt;strong&gt;collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; for the good of all. The organisations that want to survive and thrive must recognise the &lt;strong&gt;waste&lt;/strong&gt; in layers of management and see that they only serve as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;obstacles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, like a self-promoting dam, that blocks, stifles and obscures direct, meaningful communication between the team and the customer. They are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; necessary in a modern agile world, where &lt;strong&gt;the team has the most important role&lt;/strong&gt;, they have to step aside to clear a path in which ‘real’ &lt;strong&gt;value&lt;/strong&gt; can flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-birth-of-a-new-movement&quot;&gt;The birth of a new movement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to start a new movement. This movement will be known as ‘&lt;strong&gt;Natural&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Agile&lt;/strong&gt;’ as I have come to believe with &lt;em&gt;all my heart&lt;/em&gt;, that we are agile from birth and it is the most natural part of our daily existence. &lt;strong&gt;Natural&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Agile&lt;/strong&gt;, because I believe that we must align our approach to software development to take advantage of our &lt;strong&gt;instinctive&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;innate&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;abilities,&lt;/strong&gt; as we stand on the shoulders of the great thought leaders that gave birth to the original agile movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a well-defined &lt;strong&gt;schism&lt;/strong&gt; will clearly differentiate the movement, maintaining &lt;strong&gt;clarity&lt;/strong&gt; in an already crowded and confusing space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the true &lt;strong&gt;spirit&lt;/strong&gt; of agile I have no idea where this journey is going to go, but I have enough passion to take that first scary step, &lt;strong&gt;even if I fail&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At this moment, I feel as though I am lighting a candle in the dark and with a shaking hand raising it slowly to see if there is anyone else in the darkness with me, in the hope that we can join forces and unite behind this cause.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am reaching out to anyone that shares this view and &lt;strong&gt;cares&lt;/strong&gt; enough to want to ‘really’ make a change, I ask you to &lt;strong&gt;share this message around the world&lt;/strong&gt; so that &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt; we can &lt;strong&gt;take agile back!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.naturalagile.org&quot;&gt;http://www.naturalagile.org&lt;/a&gt; and leave me a comment I value your feedback :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 14:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/natural-agile.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/natural-agile.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why autonomy is so important for individuals, teams and companies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blog from my website http://www.davidboyne.co.uk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://mikehadlow.blogspot.co.il/2014/06/heisenberg-developers.html&quot;&gt;a thought provoking blog from Mike Hadlow&lt;/a&gt; which got me thinking about the importance of autonomy in teams and what it means for developers. In this post I will share from experience how autonomy can lead to motivated, self organising and passionate teams, and how dangerous things can get if teams don’t have it or it’s taken away from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teams&quot;&gt;Teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been writing software for awhile now and over the course of my career I have worked with teams that are motivated, self driven and passionate. Teams that were motivated, self driven and passionate but lost it all over time and teams that never had it. Which most of the time is due to a lack of autonomy in the team and traditional management methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short (in my opinion), traditional management consists of a hierarchy. We have a boss, the boss tells us what to do and we do it, and their boss tells them what to do (and so on). This style of management has worked for many years (and continues too), but recently I feel we are all learning that this isn’t necessary the best way to manage software teams especially developers. We have to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“…developers become disengaged, unmotivated and bored and eventually move on….”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software development is a creative process and requires a lot of brain stimulation. All members of the team are creative in way one or another but for some reason software developers sometimes have the persona of just being code monkeys (build what I say and do as I say).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some developers that just want the paycheck don’t mind this attitude, but the developers that are passionate, self driven and motivated hate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this happens developers become &lt;strong&gt;disengaged&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;unmotivated&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;bored&lt;/strong&gt; and eventually move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I have learnt is if we give individuals and teams more autonomy on what they do and how they do it they all get an increase in &lt;strong&gt;engagement&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;motivation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;passion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams that a more driven, motivated and passionate will &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; outperform teams that are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autonomy-leads-to-a-better-outcomes-for-everybody&quot;&gt;Autonomy leads to a better outcomes for everybody&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past teams and individuals I have worked with that have more autonomy with their life and job tend to be more motivated and driven. Leading to quality software, high motivated individuals and self driven teams. &lt;strong&gt;Teams that actually care about what they do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas teams with a lack of autonomy become disengaged, lose interest and motivation, leading to messy code, technical debt and attitudes where team members &lt;strong&gt;don’t necessarily care about what they do&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at successful technology companies and try to understand how they are so successful, it normally comes down to &lt;strong&gt;culture&lt;/strong&gt; and individuals/teams with drive, passion and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-it-all-come-down-too&quot;&gt;What does it all come down too?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it comes down to one thing. &lt;strong&gt;Trust&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think software craftsmanship lives in an age where old traditional management no longer works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you really want high performing motivated people and teams we need to learn how to give anatomy to them. I’m not saying just let teams decide what to do and when to do it, but guide them into decisions and work &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt; to path the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional management methods still work today, it’s why they have been around for so long, but if you want to create an atmosphere where individuals and teams are driven, motivated and passionate giving autonomy to teams &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; provide this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you enjoyed reading this I recommend you read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mikehadlow.blogspot.co.il/2014/06/heisenberg-developers.html&quot;&gt;orginal blog&lt;/a&gt; post that inspired me to write this post and also check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/184767769X?keywords=drive&amp;amp;qid=1454768318&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_3&amp;amp;sr=8-3&quot;&gt;the book Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=&#39;Why autonomy is so important for individuals, teams and companies&#39; - http://davidboyne.co.uk/2016/02/06/automany-is-important.html by @boyney123&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot;&gt;
Share on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 12:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/10/automany-is-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/10/automany-is-important.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agile is closer than you think</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout my working life I have had many different jobs … factory worker, coal miner and software engineer. Yet despite this apparent diversity I have come to realise that they all have something in common, me :) … but more specifically my desire to do the best I could at whatever it was that I was doing and take pride in my work. In the factories, I always strived to put more ‘handles on casserole dishes’ than the day before, by improving my technique, organising my equipment and putting plasters on my blisters! … when I worked in a meat factory, I challenged myself to beat my previous best time to haul 100 pork legs out of a 12 foot bath of cure with a 4 foot metal hook. When working down the pit, we pushed hard as a team to advance as far as we could by the end of the shift… making sure we left things ‘right’ for the shift following us on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as a  software developer the challenges seem endless and ever-changing and I have devoted the last 25 years trying to quench my thirst for technology, working hard to deepen my understanding and trying to keep up… the desire that has driven me is a natural part of who I am… so now it gets interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout these work experiences I have not been alone, in every place I have ever worked, I have worked shoulder to shoulder with others that have shared the same attitude, sense of pride and work ethic as me… and further in every place I have ever worked it has always been the guys/girls on the shop floor/the sharp end that really knew what was going on… where the problems were… how things could be improved and yet every time their voices were not heard… why? and what has this got to do with agile?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of working in agile teams and wrestling with books and blogs, even doing my CSM, trying to understand what this seemingly mythical intangible ‘thing called agile’ was I have come to realise that… ‘I am agile’ … my spirit and attitude, values and principles are the embodiment of agile… as is yours and that of all the other hard-working motivated people I have shared my working life with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you care about your work you are agile … if you want to work hard for your team you are agile … if you want to improve you are agile … if your highest priority is your customer guess what :) ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile is about culture, people who care and take pride in what they do, working together to do something awesome for someone else… its natural, selfless human behaviour, caring and sharing , learning and growing together… and when experienced is pure magic. When I think about those rare, special moments I have enjoyed as part of great ‘agile’ teams [Energy :)] and we got it over the line… that kind of magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please don’t get caught up in the dusty, tangled webs spun by countless weavers of confusion,terminology, rules  and process …  it mustn’t be allowed to obscure the agile light that shines in every one of us…  listen to your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software development, agile is all about the team, they are the guys on the shop floor, they live and breathe the code… they feel the pain of flaky build servers… they know and love their products better than anyone… they are ones that know best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are agile … and as an organisation, if you want to realise the true magic of agile (it’s also closer than you think!) … empower the team and they wont let you down :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe above all that ‘motivated individuals’ are at the heart of being agile… so if you care about the software you build, you’re off to great start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 10:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/agile-is-closer-than-you-think.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/agile-is-closer-than-you-think.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Dorks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a presentation about Google Dorks a couple weeks ago in which I thought it would be great to share here. This presentation was written for learning purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download presentation:
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/downloads/Google_Dorks.key&quot;&gt;Google Dorks Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 08:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/zee-google-dorks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/zee-google-dorks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lets talk Docker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation the other day with some guys who manage the on-premise infrastructure and I mentioned we were using Docker. This produced a raft of questions like “What’s Docker?”, “What’s the point of Docker”?, “Isn’t that just what VM’s are?”, “What’s a Container?” etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to hold back on diving into the technical benefits of Micro-services, Containerization, and Docker as I mentally recalled a similar conversation I had with a non-technical colleague who’s eyes quickly glazed over as I barreled headlong into described everything I know about this kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with a quick sketch about the differences between deploying an application on a regular server to what that looks like if it’s
deployed in a container and how all this is different to what these guys see every day. I talked about it being open-source and described how quick it was to get started and deploy a basic “Hello World” app and see the results in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was great because they were bought in enough at this point to organize some time to see how it worked and deploy that “Hello World” app for themselves. What was really interesting was the spin off conversation it sparked about a whole bunch of other stuff that I really wasn’t expecting. Stuff like cost savings, standardization, utilization of resources and speed to deploy and the like. Wow! Half an hour ago these guys had no idea that Docker even existed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that conversation that prompted me to write this post; I take it for granted that people know what Docker is because I live and breathe it everyday but that’s (obviously) not true for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, lets talk Docker. So the guys at Docker have kind of a mantra which is BUILD, SHIP, RUN. You can BUILD your application without worrying about stuff like environment, operating system or language. It lets you SHIP that application from the registry managing it through to distribution via a consistent UI and finally RUN and deploy that application at scale on whatever platform or provider you feel like. Cool right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is of real interest is that Docker allows you to concentrate on what you as a developer are good at i.e. writing great code, while it takes care of the infrastructure bit allowing you to use whatever platform suits you best to optimize infrastructure resources, standardize environments and at a stroke reduce that all important time to market thus increasing the ‘heartbeat’ of a tech company - i.e. how often it deploys new features to its customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker enables users to run their containers wherever they please either in a Cloud or on-premise, so you’re not locked into a vendor or Cloud provider. You can deploy your containers to any Docker host on any infrastructure from Amazon, Google, or Azure to your datacenter servers or even your laptop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardization and Resource Consolidation are also a major advantages; easily setup, reproduce, manage, update and distribute new environments. With Docker you can run as many containers as your infrastructure can handle. Just package your application and all it’s dependencies into a single container and it removes all the usual inconsistencies between environments allowing you to run the same container in any environment. Docker also plays nicely with all the popular CI/CD pipelines which is great for productivity and efficient deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whatever the problem is you’re trying to solve, large or small, Docker is a great way to spike out that mini project or deploy your enterprise web application. Google uses Docker extensively and spins up millions of containers a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So like the guys I was talking to I hope this has sparked your interest to go find out more about Docker and Containerization. It’s a really cool way to get your application out there but it also has a bunch of added benefits that can help drive down your infrastructure &amp;amp; deployment costs, standardize your environments and reduce the time it takes to get those cool new features in front of your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.docker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/&quot;&gt;https://docs.docker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 22:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/09/sb-lets-talk-docker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/09/sb-lets-talk-docker.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Peterborough.tech-community.co.uk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently moved my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidboyne.co.uk&quot;&gt;own blog platform&lt;/a&gt; over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and enjoyed the experience of learning new things along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning about DNS registry’s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-nginx-virtual-hosts-server-blocks-on-ubuntu-12-04-lts--3&quot;&gt;how to host (multiple) websites on cheap digital ocean boxes&lt;/a&gt; and also how to quickly turn out cool static websites using ruby’s Jekyll platform. Also learnt a cool new method that allows me to host a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-automatic-deployment-with-git-with-a-vps&quot;&gt;git server on the same box and allow me to push up changes straight to live within seconds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I was doing this it got me thinking of another new side project…(one I can hopefully complete)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A community driven blog, free and open source.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-project&quot;&gt;The Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With what I have learnt, I know how to manage it all technically but there are a few main issues that are out of my control:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can I find people that would contribute?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would people be interested?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do people care?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the areas I will try to focus on within the next few months. How can I drive people to share, learn and grow within the local IT community?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reaching-out-and-gaining-interest&quot;&gt;Reaching out and gaining interest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often I run &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Peterborough/&quot;&gt;IT events in Peterborough from speakers to workshops&lt;/a&gt;. Through this I have met a lot of experienced and interesting people that all live locally within the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wondered if any of the people I know from work and hosting these events would be interesting in contributing to this open source project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to the community and got a good number of people that said they were interested and would help out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hopefully this is just the &lt;strong&gt;start of this open source project&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 21:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/14/the-start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/14/the-start.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using NodeJS in Peterborough</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I currently write a lot of NodeJS at Comparethemarket and wondered if there are any other local companies also using NodeJS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we could discuss some best practices or share ideas on how to build enterprise Node applications?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could be interested start the discuss conversation below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 21:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/12/using-node.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/12/using-node.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
