<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peterborough.tech-community.co.uk</title>
    <description>Free and open source blog for IT professionals in Peterborough. Populated by anybody thats has any kind of interest in IT.
We are always looking for contributors.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 09:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 09:17:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Dorks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a presentation about Google Dorks a couple weeks ago in which I thought it would be great to share here. This presentation was written for learning purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download presentation:
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/downloads/Google_Dorks.key&quot;&gt;Google Dorks Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 08:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/zee-google-dorks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/10/zee-google-dorks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lets talk Docker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation the other day with some guys who manage the on-premise infrastructure and I mentioned we were using Docker. This produced a raft of questions like “What’s Docker?”, “What’s the point of Docker”?, “Isn’t that just what VM’s are?”, “What’s a Container?” etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to hold back on diving into the technical benefits of Micro-services, Containerization, and Docker as I mentally recalled a similar conversation I had with a non-technical colleague who’s eyes quickly glazed over as I barreled headlong into described everything I know about this kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with a quick sketch about the differences between deploying an application on a regular server to what that looks like if it’s
deployed in a container and how all this is different to what these guys see every day. I talked about it being open-source and described how quick it was to get started and deploy a basic “Hello World” app and see the results in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was great because they were bought in enough at this point to organize some time to see how it worked and deploy that “Hello World” app for themselves. What was really interesting was the spin off conversation it sparked about a whole bunch of other stuff that I really wasn’t expecting. Stuff like cost savings, standardization, utilization of resources and speed to deploy and the like. Wow! Half an hour ago these guys had no idea that Docker even existed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that conversation that prompted me to write this post; I take it for granted that people know what Docker is because I live and breathe it everyday but that’s (obviously) not true for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, lets talk Docker. So the guys at Docker have kind of a mantra which is BUILD, SHIP, RUN. You can BUILD your application without worrying about stuff like environment, operating system or language. It lets you SHIP that application from the registry managing it through to distribution via a consistent UI and finally RUN and deploy that application at scale on whatever platform or provider you feel like. Cool right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is of real interest is that Docker allows you to concentrate on what you as a developer are good at i.e. writing great code, while it takes care of the infrastructure bit allowing you to use whatever platform suits you best to optimize infrastructure resources, standardize environments and at a stroke reduce that all important time to market thus increasing the ‘heartbeat’ of a tech company - i.e. how often it deploys new features to its customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker enables users to run their containers wherever they please either in a Cloud or on-premise, so you’re not locked into a vendor or Cloud provider. You can deploy your containers to any Docker host on any infrastructure from Amazon, Google, or Azure to your datacenter servers or even your laptop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardization and Resource Consolidation are also a major advantages; easily setup, reproduce, manage, update and distribute new environments. With Docker you can run as many containers as your infrastructure can handle. Just package your application and all it’s dependencies into a single container and it removes all the usual inconsistencies between environments allowing you to run the same container in any environment. Docker also plays nicely with all the popular CI/CD pipelines which is great for productivity and efficient deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whatever the problem is you’re trying to solve, large or small, Docker is a great way to spike out that mini project or deploy your enterprise web application. Google uses Docker extensively and spins up millions of containers a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So like the guys I was talking to I hope this has sparked your interest to go find out more about Docker and Containerization. It’s a really cool way to get your application out there but it also has a bunch of added benefits that can help drive down your infrastructure &amp;amp; deployment costs, standardize your environments and reduce the time it takes to get those cool new features in front of your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.docker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/&quot;&gt;https://docs.docker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 22:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/09/sb-lets-talk-docker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/03/09/sb-lets-talk-docker.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Peterborough.tech-community.co.uk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently moved my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidboyne.co.uk&quot;&gt;own blog platform&lt;/a&gt; over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and enjoyed the experience of learning new things along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning about DNS registry’s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-nginx-virtual-hosts-server-blocks-on-ubuntu-12-04-lts--3&quot;&gt;how to host (multiple) websites on cheap digital ocean boxes&lt;/a&gt; and also how to quickly turn out cool static websites using ruby’s Jekyll platform. Also learnt a cool new method that allows me to host a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-automatic-deployment-with-git-with-a-vps&quot;&gt;git server on the same box and allow me to push up changes straight to live within seconds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I was doing this it got me thinking of another new side project…(one I can hopefully complete)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A community driven blog, free and open source.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-project&quot;&gt;The Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With what I have learnt, I know how to manage it all technically but there are a few main issues that are out of my control:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can I find people that would contribute?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would people be interested?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do people care?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the areas I will try to focus on within the next few months. How can I drive people to share, learn and grow within the local IT community?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reaching-out-and-gaining-interest&quot;&gt;Reaching out and gaining interest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often I run &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Peterborough/&quot;&gt;IT events in Peterborough from speakers to workshops&lt;/a&gt;. Through this I have met a lot of experienced and interesting people that all live locally within the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wondered if any of the people I know from work and hosting these events would be interesting in contributing to this open source project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to the community and got a good number of people that said they were interested and would help out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hopefully this is just the &lt;strong&gt;start of this open source project&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 21:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/14/the-start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/14/the-start.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using NodeJS in Peterborough</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I currently write a lot of NodeJS at Comparethemarket and wondered if there are any other local companies also using NodeJS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we could discuss some best practices or share ideas on how to build enterprise Node applications?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could be interested start the discuss conversation below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 21:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/12/using-node.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tech/2016/02/12/using-node.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
